Curt Stern Papers 1907-1981 Mss.Ms.Coll.5
American Philosophical Society
- Correspondence, 1907-1981 (Box 1-43)
  - Deutsche Akademie Der Naturforscher Leopoldina, 1975; 2 items (Box 7)
  - Development Biology Conference 1970, 1964; 2 items (Box 7)
  - Developmental Biology (Journal), 1970; 5 items (Box 7)
  - Diamond, Louis K., 1970; 3 items (Box 7)
  - Dick, Hugh G., 1957; 2 items (Box 7)
  - Dickerman, Stephen G., 1963; 2 items (Box 7)
  - Dictionary of Scientific Biography, 1967; 1 item (Box 7)
  - Dighton, Ralph, 1966; 2 items (Box 7)
  - DiPaolo, Joseph A., 1965; 2 items (Box 7)
  - Diver, C., 1929; 1 item (Box 7)
  - Dobell, Clifford, 1925; 1 item (Box 7)
  - Dobzhansky, Theodosius, 1929-1975; 5 folders (Box 7)
    Bibliographical matters; Biographical and personal data; Biographical and personal data -- Bridges, Calvin B.; California Institute of Technology; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Columbia University; Congratulations, greetings, thanks -- Stern, Curt. 70th birthday; Cytogenetics; Displaced German scholars; Drosophila genetics; Dunn, Leslie Clarence; Ephrussi, Boris; Evolution; History of biology, especially genetics; Laboratory techniques, equipment; Political issues; Population genetics; Publication -- Genetics and the Origin of Species; Recommendations; Requests for aid in finding positions; Reviews -- Lysenko, Trofim Denisovich; Rockefeller University; Russian politics and science -- Kerkis, Julius J.; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.; World War II -- Impact on science
    - Folder 1, 1929-1933; 15 items (Box 7)
    - Folder 2, 1935-1940; 23 items (Box 7)
    - Folder 3, 1940-1947; 28 items (Box 7)
    - Folder 4, 1950-1968; 26 items (Box 7)
    - Folder 5, 1970-1975; 4 items (Box 7)
  - Dobzhansky, Theodosius. "Studies on the intersexes and supersexes in Drosophila Melanogaster", 1930; 2 folders (Box 7)
    - Folder 1, 1930; 1 item (Box 7)
    - Folder 2, 1930; 1 item (Box 7)
  - Dodds, H. W. (President, Princeton University), 1947; 2 items (Box 7)
  - Dohrn, R., 1929; 1 item (Box 7)
  - Doljanski, L., 1939; 1 item (Box 7)
  - Dominican Republic, 1942; 3 items (Box 7)
  - Dougherty, Ellsworth C., 1960; 2 items (Box 7)
  - Dougherty, Ellsworth C. "Cultivation of Brachionid Rotifers", 1960; 2 items (Box 7)
  - Downs, James F., 1970; 1 item (Box 7)
  - Down's Syndrome, 1960-1961; 2 folders (Box 7)
    Cytogenetics; Genetics -- Nomenclature; Human genetics -- Down's Syndrome; Publication
    - Folder 1, 1960-1961; 27 items (Box 7)
    - Folder 2, 1961; 13 items (Box 7)
  - Doyle, Gregory G., 1970; 2 items (Box 7)
  - Draeger, R.H., 1946; 2 items (Box 7)
  - Drets, Maximo Eduardo, 1961-1968; 11 items (Box 7)
  - Dreyer, William J. "Proposed new and general chromosomal control mechanism for commitment of specific cell lines during development", 1969; 1 item (Box 7)
  - Dreyfus, Andre, 1944; 2 items (Box 7)
  - Dronamraju, K. R. (Krishna R.), 1964-1971; 2 folders (Box 7)
    Biographical and personal data -- Sherwood, Eva; Haldane, John Burdon Sanderson; Human genetics -- Hairy ears; Publication; Requests for aid in finding positions; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
    - Folder 1, 1964-1968; 15 items (Box 7)
    - Folder 2, 1969-1971; 17 items (Box 7)
  - Drosophila Information Service, 1970; 2 items (Box 7)
  - Dryden, Hugh L., 1963; 1 item (Box 7)
  - Dubinin, Nikolas P., 1931-1937; 3 items (Box 7)
  - Dublin, Louis I., 1932; 1 item (Box 7)
  - Dudley, D. Guilford, 1940; 4 items (Box 7)
  - Duke, Harry R., 1971; 2 items (Box 7)
  - Duke University. Department of Zoology, 1967; 5 items (Box 7)
  - Dumars, Kenneth W., 1971-1972; 6 items (Box 7)
  - Dunn, Leslie Clarence, 1933-1978; 6 folders (Box 7)
    American Philosophical Society -- Curt Stern Papers; Charles, Donald Randolph; Displaced German Scholars -- Braun, Joachim Werner; Displaced German scholars -- Caspari, Ernst Wilhelm; Displaced German Scholars -- Goldschmidt, Richard Benedict; Displaced German scholars -- Jollos, Victor; Drosophila genetics; Editorial matters -- Genetics; Embryology, developmental genetics; Fellowships, assistantships -- Perkins, David; Fellowships, assistantships -- Shull, Elizabeth; Fellowships, assistantships -- Steinberg, Arthur G.; Genetics Society of America; History of biology, especially genetics; Invitations -- Columbia University; Kuhn, Alfred; Laboratory techniques, equipment; Mohr, Otto Louis; Political issues; Publication -- Bodenstein, Dietrich; Publication -- Neel, James V.; Recommendations -- Brasted, Adair; Recommendations -- Kaliss, Nathan; Russian politics and science; Teaching -- Genetics; University of Rochester; World War II -- Impact on science; Zea (maize) genetics
    - Folder 1, 1933-1934; 14 items (Box 7)
    - Folder 2, 1935-1937; 25 items (Box 7)
    - Folder 3, 1938-1939; 22 items (Box 7)
    - Folder 4, 1940-1943; 22 items (Box 7)
    - Folder 5, 1944-1950; 18 items (Box 7)
    - Folder 6, 1961-1978; 19 items (Box 7)
  - DuPraw, Ernest J., 1964-1966; 9 items (Box 8)
  - Dupree, A. Hunter, 1962; 1 item (Box 8)
  - Dyck, Arthur J., 1972; 1 item (Box 8)
  - Dyson-Hudson, Rada, 1975; 1 item (Box 8)
  - Eagle, Harry, 1954; 2 items (Box 8)
  - Eakin, Richard M., 1939-1968; 3 folders (Box 8)
    -see also: University of California, Berkeley. Eakin, Richard (Chair, Dept. of Zoology, Univ. Calif., Berkeley)
    Bibliographical matters; Biographical and personal data; Fellowships, assistantships -- Kodani, Masuo; Invitations -- University of California, Berkeley; Laboratory techniques, equipment; Teaching; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
    - Folder 1, 1939-1947; 20 items (Box 8)
    - Folder 2, 1947; 14 items (Box 8)
    - Folder 3, 1947-1968; 27 items (Box 8)
  - Eakin, Richard M. Bibliography, 1964; 1 item (Box 8)
  - Eakin, Richard M. "A Professor's Days", 1971; 1 item (Box 8)
  - East, Edward M., 1934-1935; 4 items (Box 8)
  - Eckland, Bruce K., 1966; 3 items (Box 8)
  - Edelman, Gerald M., 1969; 1 item (Box 8)
  - Edgar, R. S., 1965; 1 item (Box 8)
  - Edington, Charles W., 1964-1965; 3 items (Box 8)
  - Editura Meridiane (Publisher), 1965; 2 items (Box 8)
  - Edlin, Gordon, 1972; 3 items (Box 8)
  - Edwards, Anthony, 1967; 2 items (Box 8)
  - Edwards, John, 1970-1971; 5 items (Box 8)
  - Effenberger, Hanna, 1954; 1 item (Box 8)
  - Effenberger, Walter, 1933; 1 item (Box 8)
  - Efroimson, V.P., 1964-1966; 3 items (Box 8)
  - Egelhaaf, Albrecht, 1969; 1 item (Box 8)
  - Ehling, Udo, 1965; 3 items (Box 8)
  - Ehrlich, Paul R., 1967-1969; 2 items (Box 8)
  - Ehrman, Lee, 1967-1971; 9 items (Box 8)
  - Einstein, Albert (Box 8)
    see: Bernstein, Marianne E., and Emergency Committee of Atomic Scientists
  - Eisner, Victor, 1965; 1 item (Box 8)
  - Ellison, Laurence N., 1969-1970; 5 items (Box 8)
  - Ellwanger, Janet, 1971; 2 items (Box 8)
  - El-Tobgy, H.A., 1963; 1 item (Box 8)
  - Emergency Committee of Atomic Scientists, 1946-1948; 3 items (Box 8)
  - Emerson, R.A., 1930; 1 item (Box 8)
  - Emerson, Sterling, 1947; 2 items (Box 8)
  - Encyclopaedia Britannica, 1971; 2 items (Box 8)
  - Enders, Robert Kendall, 1944; 1 item (Box 8)
  - Enders, Trudy, 1947-1948; 5 items (Box 8)
  - Eoff, Michael, 1970; 1 item (Box 8)
  - Epel, David, 1970; 1 item (Box 8)
  - Ephrussi, Boris, 1941-1955; 23 items (Box 8)
    Biographical and personal data -- Taylor-Ephrussi, Harriet; Drosophila genetics; Fellowships, assistantships -- Stern, Curt; Genetics; World War II -- France
  - Epstein, Charles Joseph, 1966-1973; 9 items (Box 8)
  - Eriksson, Aldur W., 1973; 2 items (Box 8)
  - Erlenmeyer-Kimling, L., 1966-1967; 5 items (Box 8)
  - Essen-Moller, Erik (Box 8)
  - Esser, Karl, 1967-1968; 8 items (Box 8)
  - Estrada, Rodolfo Felix, 1973; 1 item (Box 8)
  - The Eugenics Society, 1931; 1 item (Box 8)
  - Euphrasia, Sister Mary, 1943; 4 items (Box 8)
  - Euthanasia Society of America, Inc., n.d.; 1 item (Box 8)
  - Evans, Herbert M., 1964-1965; 4 items (Box 8)
  - Evenari, Michael, 1955; 2 items (Box 8)
  - Everhart, Eldon R., 1971; 2 items (Box 8)
  - Evolutionary Biology (Journal), 1968; 3 items (Box 8)
  - Ewing, Joseph, 1970; 2 items (Box 8)
  - Faberge, A. C., 1940-1953; 7 items (Box 8)
  - Fabyancic, Alan F., 1966; 3 items (Box 8)
  - Fadenrecht, Joan Claire Richard, 1973-1975; 2 items (Box 8)
  - Fahmy, Myrtle J. Bird, 1969; 5 items (Box 8)
  - Fahmy, O. G., 1955; 1 item (Box 8)
  - Failla, Giocchino, 1955; 1 item (Box 8)
  - Faillard, Hans, 1965; 2 items (Box 8)
  - Falconer, Douglas, 1936-1937; 5 items (Box 8)
  - Falek, Arthur, 1971; 2 items (Box 8)
  - Falk, Raphael, 1960-1965; 5 items (Box 8)
  - Falls, Harold F., 1958; 1 item (Box 8)
  - Fankhauser, Gerhard, 1939-1944; 3 items (Box 8)
  - Farber, Eugene M., 1970; 1 item (Box 8)
  - Farnum, Hollis B., 1947; 2 items (Box 8)
  - Fatt, Helene Van Dyk, 1964-1969; 6 items (Box 8)
  - Faulhaber, Selina H., 1972; 2 items (Box 8)
  - Fawcett, Don W., 1970; 1 item (Box 8)
  - Federly, Bertha, n.d.; 1 item (Box 8)
  - Federly, Harry (Box 8)
  - Feinstein, Robert N., 1968-1969; 8 items (Box 8)
  - Feist-Hirsch, Elisabeth, 1936; 1 item (Box 8)
  - Fialkow, Philip J., 1967; 2 items (Box 8)
  - Figler, Bernard, 1972; 1 item (Box 8)
  - Finney, David J., 1966; 1 item (Box 8)
  - Fischer, Gustav Verlag (Publisher), 1964; 1 item (Box 8)
  - Fisher, Edgar J., 1947; 1 item (Box 8)
  - Fisher, Harry L., 1966; 1 item (Box 8)
  - Fisher, Ronald M., 1965; 2 items (Box 8)
  - Flatz, G., 1968-1973; 2 items (Box 8)
  - Fleissner, Else, 1930-1944; 6 items (Box 8)
  - Fogel, Seymour, 1971-1972; 2 items (Box 8)
  - Folia Mendeliana, 1975-1977; 7 items (Box 8)
  - Forbes, Clifford, 1962; 4 items (Box 8)
  - Forbes, Tom, 1946; 1 item (Box 8)
  - Ford, C.E., 1957-1969; 18 items (Box 8)
  - Ford, E.B., 1933-1934; 2 items (Box 8)
  - Ford, Harold P., 1957; 1 item (Box 8)
  - Ford, Ray C., 1970; 3 items (Box 8)
  - Forssman, Hans, n.d.; 2 items (Box 8)
  - Foulks, James, 1941; 3 items (Box 9)
  - Fox, Martin, 1972; 1 item (Box 9)
  - Franceschetti, A., 1950; 2 items (Box 9)
  - Francisco, C.B., 1966; 1 item (Box 9)
  - Franck, Heinz J., 1940; 1 item (Box 9)
  - Franck, James, 1946; 1 item (Box 9)
  - Fraser, F. Clarke, 1961-1971; 5 items (Box 9)
  - Fraser, G.R., 1968; 2 items (Box 9)
  - Freedman, Daniel G., 1965-1966; 3 items (Box 9)
  - Freeman, William Hazen, 1966; 11 items (Box 9)
  - W. H. Freeman and Co., 1949-1972; 4 folders (Box 9)
    Behavioral genetics, IQ; Business; History of biology, especially genetics; Human genetics; Publication; Reviews -- Origin of Mendelism; Reviews -- Principles of Human Genetics
    - Folder 1, 1949-1959; 14 items (Box 9)
    - Folder 2, 1964-1966; 13 items (Box 9)
    - Folder 3, 1967-1970; 20 items (Box 9)
    - Folder 4, 1971-1972; 10 items (Box 9)
  - W. H. Freeman Foundation, 1962-1964; 9 items (Box 9)
  - Frenster, John H., 1966; 4 items (Box 9)
  - Freud, Arthur, 1945; 2 items (Box 9)
  - Freye, H. A., 1968; 1 item (Box 9)
  - Friedell, Hymer L., 1970; 6 items (Box 9)
  - Frisch, Karl von, 1933-1965; 15 items (Box 9)
    Biographical and personal data; Invitations -- University of Munchen; Political issues; Publication -- Biologie; Publication -- Population genetics; World War II -- Impact on science; Zoology--Language of bees
  - Fristrom, J., 1969; 3 items (Box 9)
  - Fritz, Mary Ann, 1969; 1 item (Box 9)
  - Frolik, E.F., 1953; 1 item (Box 9)
  - Frost, Justin, 1970-1972; 5 items (Box 9)
  - Frueh, Frances B., 1971; 2 items (Box 9)
  - Fudenberg, H. Hugh, 1969-1972; 4 items (Box 9)
  - Fuhrmann, Walter, 1968-1969; 2 items (Box 9)
  - Fujiki, Norio, 1964-1970; 6 items (Box 9)
  - Fulbright, J. William, 1956; 2 items (Box 9)
  - Fulton, John F., 1958-1959; 3 items (Box 9)
  - Fung, Sui Tong, 1968-1970; 8 items (Box 9)
  - Gadek, Andrzej, 1969; 3 items (Box 9)
  - Gaffron, Hans, 1939-1968; 9 items (Box 9)
  - Gajdusek, D. Carleton, 1942-1958; 4 items (Box 9)
  - de Garay, Alfonso L., 1967-1973; 2 folders (Box 9)
    Biographical and personal data; Human genetics; International Congress of Genetics -- Thirteenth Congress; Invitations; Recommendations -- Garcia y Bellido, Antonio; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs; Travel -- Mexico
    - Folder 1, 1967-1971; 11 items (Box 9)
    - Folder 2, 1967-1973; 17 items (Box 9)
  - Garcia-Bellido, A., 1968-1974; 14 items (Box 9)
  - Garcia-Bellido, A. and J. R. Merriam. "Genetic analysis of cell heredity...", 1971; 2 items (Box 9)
  - Garcia-Castro, Jose Miguel, 1965; 3 items (Box 9)
  - Gardner, A.W., 1970; 2 items (Box 9)
  - Gardner, Eldon J., 1958-1968; 7 items (Box 9)
  - Garfinkle, Arleen, 1968; 2 items (Box 9)
  - Garn, Stanley M., 1965; 1 item (Box 9)
  - Garrison, David, 1974; 2 items (Box 9)
  - Gartler, Stanley M., 1971-1972; 12 items (Box 9)
  - Gateff, Elisabeth, 1967; 1 item (Box 9)
  - Gates, R. Ruggles, 1945-1958; 10 items (Box 9)
  - Gates, Mrs. R. Ruggles, 1963-1971; 7 items (Box 9)
  - Gaul, H., 1970; 2 items (Box 9)
  - Gayek, Joseph, 1957; 2 items (Box 9)
  - Gedda, Luigi, 1958-1971; 9 items (Box 9)
  - Gehring, Walter, 1964-1967; 2 items (Box 9)
  - Geiger, Robert A., 1966; 2 items (Box 9)
  - Geitler, L., 1946; 4 items (Box 9)
  - Gelehrter, Thomas, 1969-1970; 2 items (Box 9)
  - General Motors Cancer Research Foundation, 1978; 1 item (Box 9)
  - Genetic Units Questionnaire, 1975; 1 item (Box 9)
  - Genetica and Bibliographia Genetica (Journal), 1964-1975; 5 items (Box 9)
  - The Genetical Society, n.d.; 1 item (Box 9)
  - Genetics (Journal), 1940-1967; 7 folders (Box 9-10)
    Biographical and personal data -- Portraits of geneticists; Business; Cytogenetics; Editorial matters -- Genetics; Genetics; Publication -- Genetics; Referee's report; World War II -- Impact on science
    - Folder 1, 1951; 1 item (Box 9)
    - Folder 2, 1951; 1 item (Box 9)
    - Folder 3, 1951; 1 item (Box 9)
    - Folder 4, 1946-1947; 18 items (Box 9)
    - Folder 5, 1948; 6 items (Box 10)
    - Folder 6, 1964-1967; 30 items (Box 10)
    - Folder 7, 1940-1946; 15 items (Box 10)
  - Genetics, Inc., 1962; 1 item (Box 10)
  - Genetics Society of America, 1940-1966; 37 items (Box 10)
    Committee activities; Conferences and symposia; Drosophila genetics; Genetics Society of America; Muller, Hermann Joseph; Political issues; Publication -- Genetics; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements; World War II -- Impact on science
  - Genetics Society of America. Committee on Aid to Geneticists Abroad, 1946-1947; 4 items (Box 10)
    Biographical and personal data; Committee activities; Cytogenetics; Displaced German scholars; Genetics Society of America -- Committee on Aid to Geneticists Abroad; Political issues; Population genetics; Russian politics and science -- Lysenko, Trofim Denisovich; Solicitations for support or contribution; World War II -- Impact on science
  - Genoves, Dr., 1972; 1 item (Box 10)
  - Gerhart, John, 1975; 1 item (Box 10)
  - Gering, Martin, 1927; 1 item (Box 10)
  - German, James, 1964-1976; 2 folders (Box 10)
    Biographical and personal data -- Stern, Curt; Cytogenetics; Haldane, John Burdon Sanderson; Human genetics; Publication; Referee's report; Teaching
    - Folder 1, 1964-1971; 7 items (Box 10)
    - Folder 2, 1971-1976; 24 items (Box 10)
  - German Genetics Society, 1971; 4 items (Box 10)
  - Gerould, John H., 1944; 3 items (Box 10)
  - Gersh, Eileen S., 1946; 2 items (Box 10)
  - Gershenson, S.M., 1930; 1 item (Box 10)
  - Gershowitz, Henry, 1968; 1 item (Box 10)
  - Gerstel, Dan, 1964; 1 item (Box 10)
  - Gesellschaft Deutscher Naturforscher und Ärzte, 1964; 5 items (Box 10)
  - Ghiselin, Michael, 1969; 1 item (Box 10)
  - Ghosh, Rekha Rani, 1963; 1 item (Box 10)
  - Gianotti, Arturo A. Fernandez, 1945; 1 item (Box 10)
  - Gibson, Elizabeth, 1965; 2 items (Box 10)
  - Giersberg, H., 1958; 1 item (Box 10)
  - Gillette, Charles L., 1944; 1 item (Box 10)
  - Gillispie, Charles C., 1972; 1 item (Box 10)
  - Glass, Bentley, 1942-1968; 5 items (Box 10)
  - Goddard, David R., 1946; 2 items (Box 10)
  - Goethe Manuscript, 1964; 8 items (Box 10)
  - Goethe Universität, Frankfurt am Main, 1947; 2 items (Box 10)
  - Gofman, John W., 1967-1970; 12 items (Box 10)
  - Goin, Coleman J., 1968; 2 items (Box 10)
  - Goldberg, Hyman, 1944; 2 items (Box 10)
  - Goldman, Joy, 1966-1967; 2 items (Box 10)
  - Goldsby, Richard Allen, 1969-1975; 4 items (Box 10)
  - Goldschmidt, Elisabeth, 1962; 4 items (Box 10)
  - Goldschmidt, Hans, 1959-1973; 3 items (Box 10)
  - Goldschmidt, Richard Benedict, 1929-1955; 7 folders (Box 10)
    Biographical and personal data -- Timofeeff-Ressovsky, Nikolai W.; Congratulations, greetings, thanks -- Goldschmidt, Richard Benedict. 70th birthday; Congratulations, greetings, thanks -- Goldschmidt, Richard Benedict. 80th birthday; Displaced German scholars; Dobzhansky, Theodosius; Drosophila genetics; Editorial matters -- Genetics; Embryology, developmental genetics; Genetics -- Lymantria; Hartmann, Max; Kaiser-Wilhelm Institutes -- Biology; Political issues; Publication; Radiation genetics; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements; University of California, Berkeley; University of Rochester; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc. -- Guestbooks; World War II -- Impact on science
    - Folder 1, 1932-1933; 3 items (Box 10)
    - Folder 2, 1929-1933; 20 items (Box 10)
    - Folder 3, 1936-1939; 16 items (Box 10)
    - Folder 4, 1941-1945; 18 items (Box 10)
    - Folder 5, 1944-1945; 5 items (Box 10)
    - Folder 6, 1946; 12 items (Box 10)
    - Folder 7, 1946-1955; 12 items (Box 10)
  - Goldschmidt, Richard (letter to L.C. Dunn, April 26, 1940), 1 item (Box 10)
  - Goldschmidt, R.B. Guest book (copy), 1921-1957; 1 item (Box 10)
  - Goldsmith, N.F., 1968; 3 items (Box 10)
  - Goldstein, Elliott, 1970; 2 items (Box 10)
  - Golomb, Harvey M., 1970; 1 item (Box 10)
  - Goodrich, Hubert B., 1929-1944; 9 items (Box 10)
  - Goodspeed, Thomas H., 1932-1933; 2 items (Box 10)
  - Goodwin, Richard H., 1946; 1 item (Box 10)
  - Goran, Piljac, 1971; 2 items (Box 10)
  - Gordon, Manuel, 1956; 2 items (Box 10)
  - Gorlin, Robert J., 1967; 2 items (Box 10)
  - Goswami, H.K., 1965-1971; 6 items (Box 10)
  - Goswami, O.B., 1970; 2 items (Box 10)
  - Gottlieb, Frederic Jay, 1965-1972; 6 items (Box 10)
  - Gottschewski, Georg H.M., 1929-1947; 4 items (Box 10)
  - Gotze, Heinz, 1975; 1 item (Box 10)
  - Gould, Adair Brasted (Mrs. Charles), 1937-1971; 2 folders (Box 10)
    Bridges, Calvin B.; Charles, Donald Randolph; Drosophila genetics; Drosophila Information Service; Editorial matters; Fellowships, assistantships -- University of Rochester; Genetics -- Habrobracon; Genetics -- Triploids; Graduate study; Mites; Neel, James V.; Publication -- Genetics; University of Delaware -- Clark, Arnold M.; University of Delaware -- Whiting, Phineas W.
    - Folder 1, 1937-1941; 31 items (Box 10)
    - Folder 2, 1942-1971; 10 items (Box 10)
  - Gould, Charles, 1944; 1 item (Box 10)
  - Gouveia, M.D., 1970; 2 items (Box 10)
  - Gowen, John W., 1941-1963; 12 items (Box 10)
  - Graham, John B. "Relation of genetics to control of human fertility", 1970; 3 items (Box 10)
  - Graham, Robert, 1972; 4 items (Box 10)
  - Grant, Robert H., 1961; 2 items (Box 10)
  - Grant, Verne, 1971; 1 item (Box 10)
  - Graves, Jenny M., 1973; 1 item (Box 10)
  - Gray, Elmer, 1971; 3 items (Box 10)
  - Gray, George W., 1948; 1 item (Box 10)
  - Gray, Peter, 1965-1971; 5 items (Box 10)
  - Green, Earl L., 1953; 2 items (Box 11)
  - Green, Melvin M., 1959-1975; 9 items (Box 11)
  - Greenblatt, David, 1966; 2 items (Box 11)
  - Greene, John C., 1960-1968; 8 items (Box 11)
  - Gregg, Alan, 1952-1955; 13 items (Box 11)
  - Gregg, Kenneth W., 1973; 2 items (Box 11)
  - Gregg, Theodora Lee, 1969; 2 items (Box 11)
  - Grether, E.T., 1968-1971; 7 items (Box 11)
  - Griem, Melvin L. "Late and subtle effects of radiation", 1969; 2 items (Box 11)
  - Griffen, A.B., 1947; 2 items (Box 11)
  - Grigliatti, Thomas, 1971; 9 items (Box 11)
  - Grim, James Franklin, 1964; 2 items (Box 11)
  - Grobman, Arnold B., 1946-1967; 3 items (Box 11)
  - Grobman, Hulda, 1960; 2 items (Box 11)
  - Gross, Grete (and husband), 1976; 3 items (Box 11)
  - Gross, Samson R., 1972-1973; 3 items (Box 11)
  - Grossbach, Ulrich, 1970; 1 item (Box 11)
  - Gruening, Ernest, 1966; 1 item (Box 11)
  - Grumbach, Melvin M., 1967-1970; 5 items (Box 11)
  - Grundbacher, Fred, 1966; 2 items (Box 11)
  - Gruneberg, Hans, 1939; 2 items (Box 11)
  - Gruss, Joh., 1929; 2 items (Box 11)
  - Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, 1962-1966; 11 items (Box 11)
  - Gunther, Dr., 1968; 2 items (Box 11)
  - Gustafsson, Axe, 1946; 1 item (Box 11)
  - Guthrie, Marjorie, 1968; 2 items (Box 11)
  - Guthrie, Mary, 1947; 2 items (Box 11)
  - Guttmacher, Alan F., 1946; 2 items (Box 11)
  - Guttman, Ruth, 1964; 2 items (Box 11)
  - Gwilliam, G.F., 1960; 2 items (Box 11)
  - Haberer, Joseph, 1968; 2 items (Box 11)
  - Hadorn, Ernst, 1939-1974; 18 items (Box 11)
    Baltzer, Fritz; Biographical and personal data; Boche, Robert D.; Bodenstein, Dietrich; Drosophila genetics; Drosophila Information Service; Editorial matters; Embryology, developmental genetics; Genetics -- Lethality; Gloor, Hans; Gottschewski, Georg H. M.; Hammerling, Joachim; Hartmann, Max; Heitz, Emil; Human genetics; International Congress of Genetics -- Seventh Congress; Lent, Fritz; Molecular genetics; Ris, Hans; Schultz, Jack; Seiler, Jakob; Spemann, Hans; Teaching; Timofeeff-Ressovsky, Nikolai W.; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements; World War II -- Impact on science
  - Hagemann, Rudolph, 1964-1973; 5 items (Box 11)
  - Hahn, Roger, 1969; 2 items (Box 11)
  - Hahn, Roger. "Memorandum on the needs of History of Science and Technology at Berkeley." June 1968, 1 item (Box 11)
  - Haldane, Charlotte, n.d.; 1 item (Box 11)
  - Haldane, J. B. S. (John Burdon Sanderson), 1929-1965; 31 items (Box 11)
    Cytogenetics; Darlington, Cyril Dean; Displaced German scholars; Drosophila genetics; Genetics of plants; Haldane, Helen Spurway; Honors -- National Academy of Sciences; Human genetics; Koller, Peo Charles; Philip, Ursula; Publication; Reviews; Travel -- India
  - Haller, Mark H., 1968; 3 items (Box 11)
  - Hamburger, Viktor, 1927-1969; 2 folders (Box 11)
    Bodenstein, Dietrich; Cairns, John; Cytogenetics; Displaced German scholars; Drosophila genetics; Editorial matters; Embryology, developmental genetics; Grobman, Arnold B.; Kaiser-Wilhelm Institutes -- Biology; Marine Biological Laboratory, Woods Hole; National Academy of Sciences; Recommendations -- Rudnick; Spemann, Hans; Teaching; Travel -- East Germany; University of Freiburg; University of Rochester -- Goddard, David Rockwell; University of Rochester -- Holtfreter, Johannes; University of Rochester -- Willier, Benjamin Harrison; Washington University (Saint Louis, Mo.); World War II -- Impact on science
    - Folder 1, 1927-1942; 17 items (Box 11)
    - Folder 2, 1943-1969; 12 items (Box 11)
  - Hamerton, John L., 1965-1974; 10 items (Box 11)
  - Hammer, Paula, 1969; 2 items (Box 11)
  - Hammerling, Joachim, 1929-1980; 4 folders (Box 11)
    Biographical and personal data; Genetics -- Acetabularia; Honors -- Royal Society (Great Britain); Kaiser-Wilhelm Institutes; Max-Planck Institutes; Political issues; Publication -- Principles of Human Genetics; Referee's report -- Moewus, Franz; Timofeeff-Ressovsky, Nikolai W.; World War II -- Impact on science
    - Folder 1, 1929-1939; 9 items (Box 11)
    - Folder 2, 1946-1954; 19 items (Box 11)
    - Folder 3, 1964-1966; 3 items (Box 11)
    - Folder 4, 1970-1980; 4 items (Box 11)
  - Hammett, Frederick S., 1939-1941; 22 items (Box 11)
    Drosophila genetics; Invitations -- Lankenau Hospital Research Institute; Invitations -- Marine Experimental Station; Laboratory techniques, equipment; Publication; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs -- Growth Society; University of Rochester -- Willier, Benjamin Harrison